

CHRIS FAROUER

cjamesegr@gmail.com



www.linkedin.com/in/chris-farquer in



12010 Vista Nogal, San Antonio, TX 📅



Highly motivated and focused Electrical Engineer with 8 years of experience. Driven to succeed and contribute with the ability to work both independently and collaboratively across departments. Committed to continuous learning, I stay abreast of emerging trends and technologies in the field to deliver cutting-edge solutions. Proven technical skills with flexibility to work outside of the job description to complete projects on time within budget.

Professional Experience

March 2020 - Present

Electrical Engineer III / Equipment Manager

Xenex Disinfection Services – 1074 Arion Cir, Suite 116, San Antonio, TX 78216

- Develop Standard Operating Procedures (SOPs) which abide by 60601 and NIST standards.
- Write qualification documents, reports, manufacturing work instructions, verification and validation protocols for quality assurance purposes.
- Actively involved in full life design cycle, from requirement definition through design, prototyping, proof of concept and implementation that abide by safety regulations.
- Created a graphical user interface for the production framework that allowed the technician to select the target subsystem for flashing firmware.
- Define product requirements and identify best concepts
- Created thorough and efficient test and production protocols which reduced production time by 15%.

August 2018 - March 2020

Electrical Engineer II

Xenex Disinfection Services – 121 Interpark Blvd, Suite 104, San Antonio, TX 78216

- Integral in the design, development, simulation, testing and integration of hardware for UV disinfection robotic systems.
- Contribute to firmware development.
- PCB design, debugging, prototyping circuits and software.
- Coordinated the student intern program.

- Diagnose or analyze the performance of electrical components, assemblies and systems.
- Designed a remote RF communication with LCD system that increased customer product engagement by 35%.
- Designed cable harnesses and system level wiring schematics.
- Drafted assembly instructions for aiding in manufacturing.

DECEMBER 2014 - AUGUST 2018

Electrical Engineer I

Xenex Disinfection Services – 121 Interpark Blvd, Suite 104, San Antonio, TX 78216

- Conduct photonic and spectroscopy tests to analyze UV disinfection properties.
- Design and implement microcontroller applications for automated testing.
- Rapid design, fabrication and prototyping of electrical and mechanical test fixtures.
- Operate specialized testing equipment and computer-assisted engineering software to perform engineering tasks.
- Devise, fabricate and assemble new or modified components for experimental testing.
- Analyze tests results in relation to design or rated specifications and test objectives, and modify or adjust the equipment to meet specifications.
- Instructed and trained technicians on production procedures.
- Contributed to design reviews and updating documents as needed.

Skills

- Hardware / Firmware Design and Testing
- Altium Computer-Aided Design (CAD) and Schematic Capture
- Microcontrollers / Embedded Systems
- Proficiency in Python, C++, React Native

- Failure Analysis, Electrical Testing and Troubleshooting
- Technical report writing and documentation skills
- Product Design, Development and Support
- Ability to work effectively in multidisciplinary teams

Education

August 2014

Bachelor Of Science in Electrical Engineering

University Of Texas At San Antonio - San Antonio, TX